[
  {
    "question": "How many books does the New Testament have?",
    "correctAnswer": "27",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "26",
      "66",
      "39"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000001"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah name her child?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Saul",
      "Samson",
      "Gideon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20",
    "id": "000002"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was responsible for the massacre of children in Bethlehem shortly after Jesus's birth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Herod",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Pilate",
      "The High Priest",
      "Quirinius"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 1",
    "id": "000003"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus healed Peter's mother-in-law. What was wrong with her?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fever",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Paralysis",
      "Blind in one eye",
      "Bleeding"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1",
    "id": "000004"
  },
  {
    "question": "What promise do the meek receive from the Lord Jesus in the Beatitudes?",
    "correctAnswer": "They shall inherit the earth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "For them is the kingdom of heaven",
      "They shall be called children of God",
      "They shall see God"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:5",
    "id": "000005"
  },
  {
    "question": "What promise follows the Beatitude 'blessed are the pure in heart'?",
    "correctAnswer": "they shall see God",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "For them is the kingdom of heaven",
      "They shall be called children of God",
      "They shall inherit the earth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:8",
    "id": "000006"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet was not allowed to marry by the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jeremiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 16:2",
    "id": "000007"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet was commanded to marry by the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hosea",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Jeremiah",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 1:2",
    "id": "000008"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet and his children were a symbol for Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isaiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jeremiah",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000009"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet lost his wife during his time as a prophet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ezekiel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Jeremiah",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 24:16-24",
    "id": "000010"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 1st day God created...",
    "correctAnswer": "the light",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "man",
      "plants",
      "fish"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:4",
    "id": "000011"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 2nd day there was separation between...",
    "correctAnswer": "sea and sky",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "sea and land",
      "light and darkness",
      "light and land"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:6-8",
    "id": "000012"
  },
  {
    "question": "God rested on the...",
    "correctAnswer": "7th day",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1st day",
      "5th day",
      "6th day"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2:2",
    "id": "000013"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the tree of the knowledge of good and evil?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the garden of Eden",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In the garden of Aden",
      "Just outside the garden of Eden",
      "In Shinar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2 and 3",
    "id": "000014"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was murdered by Cain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "His mother",
      "His father",
      "Esau"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000015"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Methuselah when he died?",
    "correctAnswer": "969",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "996",
      "966",
      "669"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 5:27",
    "id": "000016"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long did Noah stay in the ark with his family?",
    "correctAnswer": "Just over a year",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "40 days",
      "7 months",
      "1.5 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 8",
    "id": "000017"
  },
  {
    "question": "The top of the tower of Babel was meant to reach into ...",
    "correctAnswer": "the heavens",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the clouds",
      "great height",
      "an invisible height"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:4",
    "id": "000018"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word 'Babel' mean?",
    "correctAnswer": "Confusion",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Great city",
      "Great tower",
      "Destruction"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11",
    "id": "000019"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Abram born?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ur of the Chaldeans",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Canaan",
      "Egypt",
      "Shinar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26",
    "id": "000020"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Abram's father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Terah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lot",
      "Isaac",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26",
    "id": "000021"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Abram go to Canaan?",
    "correctAnswer": "God asked him to",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There was plenty of work",
      "Family already lived there",
      "There was enough to eat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12",
    "id": "000022"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Abram's wife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sarai",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rebekah",
      "Rachel",
      "Zilpah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11",
    "id": "000023"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Abram and Sarai go to Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "There was a famine in Canaan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There was much money to earn",
      "They went to visit relatives",
      "It was a command from the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12:10",
    "id": "000024"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abram and Lot return to Canaan. Where does Lot live?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the Jordan region",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On the coast",
      "In the mountains",
      "In Sodom"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19",
    "id": "000025"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sarai remains barren. Who becomes Abram's second wife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hagar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Zilpah",
      "Bilhah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:3",
    "id": "000026"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abram and Hagar have a son, his name is...",
    "correctAnswer": "Ishmael",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lot",
      "Isaac",
      "Jacob"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:11",
    "id": "000027"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Lot's wife do?",
    "correctAnswer": "She looked back while leaving Sodom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "She warned her husband Lot",
      "She stayed in Sodom",
      "She did what God asked her to do"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19:26",
    "id": "000028"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abraham and Sarah finally have a son. How old was Abraham then?",
    "correctAnswer": "100",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "80",
      "90",
      "120"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 21:5",
    "id": "000029"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where should Abraham sacrifice Isaac?",
    "correctAnswer": "On Mount Moriah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On Mount Sinai",
      "On Mount Carmel",
      "On Mount Horeb"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22:2",
    "id": "000030"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who does Isaac marry?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rebekah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Bilhah",
      "Sarah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 24:67",
    "id": "000031"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who succeeds Moses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joshua",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Caleb",
      "Elijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 1:1",
    "id": "000032"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Moses strike the rock?",
    "correctAnswer": "at Meribah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "at Edom",
      "at Mara",
      "at Elim"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 17:7",
    "id": "000033"
  },
  {
    "question": "After ... much of Canaan is conquered",
    "correctAnswer": "7 years",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "4 years",
      "6 years",
      "9 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua",
    "id": "000034"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Joshua's death...",
    "correctAnswer": "there is no leader anymore",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "his son succeeds him",
      "Judah succeeds him",
      "Eleazar succeeds him"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 24",
    "id": "000035"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Israel's first task after Joshua's death?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fight against the remaining Canaanites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Finding a new leader",
      "The people got a period of rest",
      "Finding water sources"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 1:1",
    "id": "000036"
  },
  {
    "question": "After a long period following Joshua's death comes...",
    "correctAnswer": "a judge",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "a king",
      "an emperor",
      "a prophet"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9",
    "id": "000037"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first judge?",
    "correctAnswer": "Othniel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ehud",
      "Samgar",
      "Barak"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9",
    "id": "000038"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under the leadership of the first judge...",
    "correctAnswer": "people serve God again",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "people serve the idols again",
      "the enemy is driven away",
      "the people become rebellious again"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3: 9, 10",
    "id": "000039"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who are the most well-known judges?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gideon, Samson and Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Saul, David and Solomon",
      "Jephthah, Deborah and Barak",
      "Othniel, Ehud and Samgar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges",
    "id": "000040"
  },
  {
    "question": "With how many men did Gideon drive away a large army of Midianites?",
    "correctAnswer": "300 men",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1000 men",
      "100 men",
      "500 men"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 7:6",
    "id": "000041"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the last judge?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Eli",
      "Samson",
      "Jephthah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel",
    "id": "000042"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which answer does not belong. Samson may NOT ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "not marry",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "not drink wine or beer",
      "not cut his hair",
      "not touch dead bodies"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 13",
    "id": "000043"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deborah defeated the ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "Canaanites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Midianites",
      "Ammonites",
      "Philistines"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 4",
    "id": "000044"
  },
  {
    "question": "Several judges are mentioned as heroes of faith in the Epistle to the Hebrews. Which judge is NOT mentioned in it?",
    "correctAnswer": "Deborah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Gideon",
      "Samson",
      "Samuel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Hebrews 11",
    "id": "000045"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who leads the people after Samuel?",
    "correctAnswer": "King Saul",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "King David",
      "High Priest Eli",
      "Judge Samson"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000046"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Saul",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Solomon",
      "Herod"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000047"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul is anointed by Samuel ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "anointed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "crowned",
      "consecrated",
      "baptized"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000048"
  },
  {
    "question": "But I hate him, because he prophesies nothing good about me, but evil. Who said that?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ahab",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Micaiah",
      "Jezebel",
      "Baasha"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 22:8",
    "id": "000049"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which time period does the story of Ruth take place?",
    "correctAnswer": "Time of Judges",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Time of Kings",
      "Exile",
      "Time of Prophets"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis",
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000050"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which place did Elimelech and Naomi come?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bethlehem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Cana",
      "Moab"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:1",
    "id": "000051"
  },
  {
    "question": "What were the names of the women whom Naomi's sons married?",
    "correctAnswer": "Orpah and Ruth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Orpah and Rebekah",
      "Ruth and Rachel",
      "Ruth and Rebekah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:4",
    "id": "000052"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Naomi want to be called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mara",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Martha",
      "Mary",
      "Miriam"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:20",
    "id": "000053"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was Boaz kind to Ruth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ruth's devotion to Naomi touched him",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He was in love with Ruth",
      "Because he was related to Naomi",
      "God asked this of him"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 2:11",
    "id": "000054"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a kinsman-redeemer?",
    "correctAnswer": "A close relative who has the duty to help another family member",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A close relative",
      "A close relative who has much money",
      "A close relative who lives in the same place"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 3:9",
    "id": "000055"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Boaz give as proof of his redemption?",
    "correctAnswer": "His sandal",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A clay tablet",
      "His ring",
      "His coat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:7",
    "id": "000056"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Boaz and Ruth's son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Obed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Judah",
      "Machlon",
      "Chilion"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17",
    "id": "000057"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Obed become father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jesse",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaac",
      "Ishmael",
      "Issachar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17",
    "id": "000058"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Jesse become father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Of King David",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Of King Solomon",
      "Of King Saul",
      "Of King Abijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 17:12",
    "id": "000059"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wives did Elkanah have?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:2",
    "id": "000060"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the old priest think when Hannah prayed in the temple?",
    "correctAnswer": "That she was drunk",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "That she was praying earnestly",
      "That she was sad",
      "That she was tired"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:14",
    "id": "000061"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah name her son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Samson",
      "Gideon",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20",
    "id": "000062"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Samuel mean?",
    "correctAnswer": "Asked of God",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Man of God",
      "Comforter",
      "God gives"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:17",
    "id": "000063"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Hannah bring Samuel?",
    "correctAnswer": "To Eli",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "To Jerusalem",
      "To Elijah",
      "To the temple in Jerusalem"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1: 25",
    "id": "000064"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah NOT bring with her when she brought Samuel to Eli?",
    "correctAnswer": "2 measures of barley",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3 bulls",
      "an ephah of flour",
      "a flask of wine"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:24",
    "id": "000065"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who thought that Samuel called him?",
    "correctAnswer": "Eli",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hophni",
      "Phinehas",
      "the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 3",
    "id": "000066"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which position did Samuel NOT hold in his life?",
    "correctAnswer": "King",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Prophet",
      "Priest",
      "Judge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel",
    "id": "000067"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the holy city called in Ezekiel 48?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Lord is there",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Zion",
      "Jerusalem",
      "City of God"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35",
    "id": "000068"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which psalm is often called the Shepherd's Psalm?",
    "correctAnswer": "Psalm 23",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Psalm 1",
      "Psalm 25",
      "Psalm 42"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalm 23",
    "id": "000069"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you call a male sheep?",
    "correctAnswer": "A ram",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A buck",
      "A lamb",
      "An ewe"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22",
    "id": "000070"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which instrument did David often play?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harp",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Harp",
      "Flute",
      "Cymbal"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 and 2 Samuel",
    "id": "000071"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the biblical book of Proverbs?",
    "correctAnswer": "Solomon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Asaph",
      "Jehoshaphat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs",
    "id": "000072"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the beginning of wisdom?",
    "correctAnswer": "The fear of the Lord",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The knowledge of the Lord",
      "The instruction of the Lord",
      "The thoughtfulness of the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:7",
    "id": "000073"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is God to those who walk uprightly?",
    "correctAnswer": "A Shield",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A Fortress",
      "A Refuge",
      "A High Tower"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 2:7",
    "id": "000074"
  },
  {
    "question": "With what must one honor the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "With possessions",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "With prayer",
      "With wisdom",
      "With sincerity"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3:9",
    "id": "000075"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is more precious than rubies?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Love",
      "Virtue",
      "Knowledge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3: 13-15",
    "id": "000076"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who must be saved?",
    "correctAnswer": "Those in danger of death",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Those who waver",
      "Those who wander",
      "Those who live godlessly"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 24:11",
    "id": "000077"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wisdom is like ... ?",
    "correctAnswer": "a beautiful crown on the head",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "a golden necklace around the neck",
      "an ornament of knowledge",
      "a band of insight"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:9",
    "id": "000078"
  },
  {
    "question": "From where must our foot remain distant?",
    "correctAnswer": "From evil",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From the path of the wicked",
      "From uneven paths",
      "From paths of death"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:14",
    "id": "000079"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many things are an abomination to the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Seven",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Five",
      "Six",
      "Three"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 6:16",
    "id": "000080"
  },
  {
    "question": "What covers love?",
    "correctAnswer": "All transgressions",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "All greed",
      "All unkindness",
      "All hatred"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 10:12",
    "id": "000081"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is in the house of a righteous man?",
    "correctAnswer": "A great treasure",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Love and faithfulness",
      "Understanding",
      "Knowledge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 15:6",
    "id": "000082"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who will fall into a pit?",
    "correctAnswer": "He who digs a pit",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Who shoots burning arrows",
      "Who is wise in his own eyes",
      "Who honors a fool"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 26:27",
    "id": "000083"
  },
  {
    "question": "When does one find mercy?",
    "correctAnswer": "When one confesses and forsakes sins",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "When one is a man of understanding",
      "When one loves in secret",
      "When one does not harden his heart"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 28:13",
    "id": "000084"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Jesus grow up?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Capernaum"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 2:23",
    "id": "000085"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days was Jesus tempted by the devil:",
    "correctAnswer": "40 days",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3 days",
      "10 days",
      "7 weeks"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1:13",
    "id": "000086"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what should one build their life's house?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rock",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sand",
      "A mountain",
      "Clay ground"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 7:25",
    "id": "000087"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Jesus say: I have not found such great faith even in Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "The centurion",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "The leper",
      "The blind man"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:10",
    "id": "000088"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Matthew when Jesus called him?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the tax office",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On the temple grounds",
      "In a tree",
      "In front of his house"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 9:9",
    "id": "000089"
  },
  {
    "question": "How big must our faith be according to Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Like a mustard seed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Like a mountain",
      "Like a rock",
      "Like a cedar of Lebanon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 17:20",
    "id": "000090"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times must we forgive each other?",
    "correctAnswer": "70 x 7 times",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7 times",
      "3 times",
      "always"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 18:22",
    "id": "000091"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who cried out: Lord, Son of David, have mercy on us",
    "correctAnswer": "2 blind men",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "10 lepers",
      "the children",
      "the lame"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 20:30",
    "id": "000092"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree was cursed by Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "The fig tree",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The olive tree",
      "The cedar",
      "The date palm"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 11:21",
    "id": "000093"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "John",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "Peter",
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 1:1",
    "id": "000094"
  },
  {
    "question": "To how many churches did John write a letter?",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "6",
      "8",
      "5"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation",
    "id": "000095"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was John told to write to Ephesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "You have left your first love",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Be faithful unto death",
      "I have given you an open door",
      "And I will give you each according to your works"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:4",
    "id": "000096"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will Jesus give the church in Smyrna if they remain faithful?",
    "correctAnswer": "The crown of life",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A white stone",
      "A new name",
      "Hidden manna"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:10",
    "id": "000097"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which teaching did they in Pergamum cling?",
    "correctAnswer": "The teaching of Balaam",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The teaching of the Pharisees",
      "There is no resurrection",
      "The teaching of Paul"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:14",
    "id": "000098"
  },
  {
    "question": "What woman did they allow in Thyatira?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jezebel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the wife of Herod",
      "The wife of Potiphar",
      "Salome"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2: 20-23",
    "id": "000099"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what will Jesus keep the church of Philadelphia?",
    "correctAnswer": "The hour of trial",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From poverty",
      "From diseases",
      "From spiritual decline"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:10",
    "id": "000100"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why will Jesus spew Laodicea out of His mouth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Because they are lukewarm",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Because they are hot",
      "Because they are cold",
      "Because they are hard"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3: 15, 16",
    "id": "000101"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was around God's throne in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "A rainbow",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A light",
      "Golden rays",
      "A cloud"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:3",
    "id": "000102"
  },
  {
    "question": "And around the throne were thrones; and on the thrones I saw ... elders sitting, clothed in white robes, and they had golden crowns on their heads. ",
    "correctAnswer": "24",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7",
      "7 x 7",
      "3"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:4",
    "id": "000103"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the great multitude that no one could count have in their hands?",
    "correctAnswer": "Palm branches",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Torches",
      "Trumpets",
      "Bowls of incense"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 7:9",
    "id": "000104"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does God do with the people who come out of the great tribulation?",
    "correctAnswer": "God will wipe away every tear from their eyes",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "God will give them a new name",
      "God will seal their foreheads",
      "God will dwell among them"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21:4",
    "id": "000105"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened when the third angel sounded?",
    "correctAnswer": "A great star, blazing like a torch, fell from the sky",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The smoke of incense with the prayers of the saints ascended",
      "There became hail and fire mixed with blood",
      "Something like a great mountain, burning with fire, was thrown into the sea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 8:10",
    "id": "000106"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the angel of the bottomless pit in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abaddon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lucifer",
      "The dragon",
      "The beast"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 9:11",
    "id": "000107"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was John told to eat in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "A little book",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A honey cake",
      "Bread",
      "Figs"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 10:9",
    "id": "000108"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many witnesses will prophesy for 1260 days?",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "7",
      "12"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 11: 3-12",
    "id": "000109"
  },
  {
    "question": "And the woman fled to the ... , where she had a place prepared by God",
    "correctAnswer": "wilderness",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "temple",
      "mountains",
      "city"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 12:6",
    "id": "000110"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bowls of wrath are there?",
    "correctAnswer": "Seven",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Three",
      "Five",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 16",
    "id": "000111"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city comes down from heaven?",
    "correctAnswer": "The new Jerusalem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The city of God",
      "The city with many dwellings",
      "That city which has foundations"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21: 1-4",
    "id": "000112"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Spirit and the Bride say?",
    "correctAnswer": "Come",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Amen",
      "Hallelujah",
      "I am the Alpha and the Omega"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 22:17",
    "id": "000113"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many letters are there from Paul to the Corinthians?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Corinthians",
      "2 Corinthians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": " 1 and 2 Corinthians",
    "id": "000114"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people did Jesus raise from the dead?",
    "correctAnswer": "Three",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "One",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Gospels",
    "id": "000115"
  },
  {
    "question": "For approximately how many years did Jesus preach?",
    "correctAnswer": "Three",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "One",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "In the Gospels",
    "id": "000116"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did they drive Jesus out of town, to the edge of the mountain, to throw Him into the abyss?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Samaria"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 4:29",
    "id": "000117"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city was Bartimaeus sitting by the gate begging?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jericho",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Samaria",
      "Capernaum"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 10:46",
    "id": "000118"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom was it asked: Do you also understand what you are reading?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Ethiopian eunuch",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Philip",
      "Peter",
      "Saul"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 8:30",
    "id": "000119"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which island did Paul and Barnabas visit on their first missionary journey?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyprus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Crete",
      "Malta",
      "Sicily"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 13:4",
    "id": "000120"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which king became severely ill, a terminal illness?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hezekiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ahaz",
      "Manasseh",
      "Jehudah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Hezekiah 20:1",
    "id": "000121"
  },
  {
    "question": "After fleeing from Queen Jezebel, where did Elijah flee to the cave? Which one?",
    "correctAnswer": "The cave on Mount Horeb",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The cave of Machpelah",
      "The cave of Adullam",
      "The caves of Zephaniah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 19",
    "id": "000122"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the Israelites NOT take with them from the Egyptians when they left Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Food",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Gold",
      "Silver",
      "Clothing"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 3:22",
    "id": "000123"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long was Paul imprisoned in Caesarea during the time of Felix and Festus?",
    "correctAnswer": "2 years",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1.5 years",
      "2.5 years",
      "3 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts",
    "id": "000124"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which deacon was stoned in Jerusalem?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stephen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Philip",
      "Timon",
      "Nicholas"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 7: 54 - 60",
    "id": "000125"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which son wanted to push David from the throne?",
    "correctAnswer": "Absalom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Joab",
      "Amnon",
      "Adonijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 15",
    "id": "000126"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the first to visit Jesus after His birth?",
    "correctAnswer": "The shepherds",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The wise men",
      "King Herod",
      "Zacharias and Elizabeth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 2: 8-20",
    "id": "000127"
  },
  {
    "question": "10 lepers were healed by Jesus. Who came back to thank Him?",
    "correctAnswer": "A Samaritan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "An Israelite",
      "A Jew",
      "A Tax Collector"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 17:11-19",
    "id": "000128"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was king when Daniel was thrown into the lion's den?",
    "correctAnswer": "Darius",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Nebuchadnezzar",
      "Belshazzar",
      "Cyrus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 6",
    "id": "000129"
  },
  {
    "question": "Peter's mother-in-law was healed of fever. In which place was this?",
    "correctAnswer": "Capernaum",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Cana",
      "Nain",
      "Jericho"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:14",
    "id": "000130"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inhabitants of the Ten-Tribe Kingdom were taken to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Assyria",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Babylon",
      "Persia",
      "Egypt"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 17:6",
    "id": "000131"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which 2 tribes did the Two-Tribe Kingdom consist?",
    "correctAnswer": "Judah and Benjamin",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Levi and Judah",
      "Joseph and Benjamin",
      "Judah and Levi"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 12:21",
    "id": "000132"
  },
  {
    "question": "3 names are for the same lake/sea. Which one doesn't belong?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Dead Sea",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sea of Galilee",
      "Sea of Gennesaret",
      "Sea of Tiberias"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000133"
  },
  {
    "question": "A new apostle was chosen instead of Judas. Who was that?",
    "correctAnswer": "Matthias",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Justus",
      "Philip",
      "Nathanael"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1:26",
    "id": "000134"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do we think of at Easter?",
    "correctAnswer": "The resurrection of Jesus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The birth of Jesus",
      "The death of Jesus",
      "The ascension of Jesus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 16",
    "id": "000135"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniel received a Babylonian name. Which one?",
    "correctAnswer": "Belteshazzar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Belshazzar",
      "Shadrach",
      "Meshach"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 1:7",
    "id": "000136"
  },
  {
    "question": "The blind man had to wash in ... to become seeing.",
    "correctAnswer": "the pool of Siloam",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the pool of Bethesda",
      "the Jordan",
      "the pool of cleansing"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "John 9: 1-7",
    "id": "000137"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the battle against Egypt, king ... of Judah fell.",
    "correctAnswer": "Josiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Amon",
      "Manasseh",
      "Ahaz"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 35: 20-24",
    "id": "000138"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the first Christian church arise?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jerusalem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Antioch",
      "Philippi",
      "Corinth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 2:40-41",
    "id": "000139"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the third and fourth disciples of Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "John and James",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Simon and Andrew",
      "Simon and James",
      "John and Andrew"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1: 16-20",
    "id": "000140"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elijah, Ahab and the people went to offer on Mount ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Carmel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Horeb",
      "Sinai",
      "Tabor"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 18: 20 -40",
    "id": "000141"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?",
    "correctAnswer": "Amen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Come",
      "Thanks be to God",
      "Blessing"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 22:21",
    "id": "000142"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who heard a Great Voice from Heaven say: 'Behold, the tabernacle of God is with the people and He will dwell with them'?",
    "correctAnswer": "John",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "James",
      "Jesus Himself"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21:3",
    "id": "000143"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Rider on the white horse called in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Faithful and True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Savior",
      "Christ Jesus",
      "Firm and certain"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 19:11",
    "id": "000144"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the sentence: Woe, woe, the great city ... , the strong city",
    "correctAnswer": "Babylon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jericho",
      "Jerusalem",
      "Nineveh"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 18:10",
    "id": "000145"
  },
  {
    "question": "How often was the trumpet blown in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "7 times",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7 times 70 times",
      "70 times",
      "700 times"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 8, 9, 10, 11",
    "id": "000146"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many seals are opened in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "8",
      "6",
      "3"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 6, 7, 8",
    "id": "000147"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who alone could open the book with the 7 seals?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Lamb",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Rock",
      "The beast with 7 eyes",
      "No one"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 5",
    "id": "000148"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was in the Letter of Christ to Sardis?",
    "correctAnswer": "You have a name that you live, and you are dead",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Woe to you",
      "The rules that church had to follow",
      "To you is Eternal Life"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:1",
    "id": "000149"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did John write the biblical book of Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "On the island of Patmos",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In prison",
      "John didn't write Revelation",
      "In the wilderness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 1:9",
    "id": "000150"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Jude warn against in his biblical book?",
    "correctAnswer": "Against false teachers",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Against the devil",
      "Against sin",
      "Against the world"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Jude"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jude 1",
    "id": "000151"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom did John write his letter, 3 John?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gaius",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The church of Laodicea",
      "To no one specific",
      "To Diotrephes"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "3 John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "3 John 1:1",
    "id": "000152"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which place did John write his letter, 2 John?",
    "correctAnswer": "From Ephesus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From Corinth",
      "From Asia Minor",
      "That is unknown"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 John",
    "id": "000153"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet told King Hezekiah that he had to die?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isaiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jeremiah",
      "Micah",
      "Amos"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 38:1",
    "id": "000154"
  },
  {
    "question": "From whom did Peter cut off the ear?",
    "correctAnswer": "Malchus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Matthew",
      "Maltus",
      "Caiaphas"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "John 18:10",
    "id": "000155"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the Macedonian man ask in Paul's dream?",
    "correctAnswer": "'Come over to Macedonia and help us'",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "'Come over and help us'",
      "'Come and see'",
      "'Come over to Macedonia and preach the gospel'"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 16:9",
    "id": "000156"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which punishment did the prophet Elijah announce to King Ahab?",
    "correctAnswer": "There shall be no dew or rain",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There shall be no more rain",
      "Famine will come",
      "Many people will die"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 17:1",
    "id": "000157"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the father of Samuel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elkanah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Elihu",
      "Elam",
      "Jeroboam"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:1",
    "id": "000158"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did Paul speak about the unknown God?",
    "correctAnswer": "In Athens",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In Corinth",
      "In Philippi",
      "In Thyatira"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts",
      "Romans"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 17:23",
    "id": "000159"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who went along on Paul and Barnabas's first missionary journey?",
    "correctAnswer": "John Mark",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Mark",
      "John",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 13",
    "id": "000160"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the sons of Zebedee?",
    "correctAnswer": "James and John",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "John and Andrew",
      "Andrew and Peter",
      "James and Peter"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1: 19 , 20",
    "id": "000161"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which place was David proclaimed king?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hebron",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Judah",
      "Gilead"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 2:4",
    "id": "000162"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said: 'You almost persuade me to become a Christian'?",
    "correctAnswer": "King Agrippa",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Silas",
      "Governor Felix",
      "King David"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 26:28",
    "id": "000163"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the wilderness journey the water was bitter at ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Mara",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Elim",
      "Rephidim",
      "Kadesh Barnea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 15:23",
    "id": "000164"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which idolatry did King Jeroboam introduce?",
    "correctAnswer": "The service of the golden calves",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The service of Baal",
      "The service of Ashtoreth",
      "The service of the stars"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 12: 25-33",
    "id": "000165"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys did Paul make?",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "2",
      "4",
      "5"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts",
    "id": "000166"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which mountain was the Ascension of Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mount of Olives",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Horeb",
      "Moriah",
      "Nebo"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1: 9-12",
    "id": "000167"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Jesus's mother live?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Bethlehem",
      "Jerusalem",
      "That is unknown"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Luke"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 1:26",
    "id": "000168"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days are there between Ascension and Pentecost?",
    "correctAnswer": "10",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "40",
      "3",
      "12"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Pentecost",
      "Ascension"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1 and 2",
    "id": "000169"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Christian to die for his faith?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stephen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "James",
      "Philip"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 7: 54-60",
    "id": "000170"
  },
  {
    "question": "Blessed is the man who does not ... in the counsel of the wicked",
    "correctAnswer": "walk",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "walk",
      "stand",
      "go"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 1:1",
    "id": "000171"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Aaron's wife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elisheba",
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Zipporah",
      "Jehosheba",
      "Elizabeth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 6:22",
    "id": "000172"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did the people react when the law was read aloud by Ezra?",
    "correctAnswer": "They wept",
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Nehemiah"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "They rejoiced",
      "They left the city",
      "They rebelled"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 8:9",
    "id": "000173"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Nehemiah's function at the court of the king of Persia?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cupbearer",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Nehemiah"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Head of the guards",
      "Herald",
      "Bookkeeper"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 1:11",
    "id": "000174"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Ezra's main task when he came to Jerusalem?",
    "correctAnswer": "Teach the people in the Law of the Lord",
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rebuild the city",
      "Restore the walls",
      "Cleanse the temple"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 7:10",
    "id": "000175"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened to King Uzziah when he wanted to perform the priestly office?",
    "correctAnswer": "He got leprosy",
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He was blessed",
      "He became king over all tribes",
      "He was expelled from Jerusalem"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 26: 16-21",
    "id": "000176"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Solomon do after he completed the temple?",
    "correctAnswer": "He prayed",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He left Jerusalem",
      "He destroyed the high places",
      "He hid the ark"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 8: 22, 23",
    "id": "000177"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who brought the ark of God to Jerusalem, after it had first failed?",
    "correctAnswer": "David",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Moses",
      "Saul",
      "Joab"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 6: 12-15",
    "id": "000178"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Elisha do to make the bitter water of Jericho healthy?",
    "correctAnswer": "He threw salt into the spring",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He prayed to God",
      "He struck the water with his cloak",
      "He commanded the water to stand still"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 2:21",
    "id": "000179"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened at the dedication of the temple that Solomon built?",
    "correctAnswer": "The cloud filled the house of the Lord",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Fire came from heaven",
      "The ark disappeared",
      "The priests went into the sanctuary"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 8: 10, 11",
    "id": "000180"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did David do when he heard of the death of Absalom?",
    "correctAnswer": "He wept and mourned",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He celebrated",
      "He fled",
      "He stoned himself"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 18:33",
    "id": "000181"
  },
  {
    "question": "With how many men did Gideon defeat the army of Midian?",
    "correctAnswer": "300",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "30",
      "1000",
      "3000"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 7:6",
    "id": "000182"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the only female judge of Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Deborah",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hannah",
      "Ruth",
      "Jael"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 4:4-5",
    "id": "000183"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Joshua say to the people in his farewell speech?",
    "correctAnswer": "But as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Leave this land, for it is unclean",
      "Seek for yourself another god this day",
      "Let us return to Egypt"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 24:15",
    "id": "000184"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Moses have to do to get water from the rock at Meribah?",
    "correctAnswer": "Strike the rock with his staff",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis",
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Speak to the rock",
      "Pray to the Lord",
      "Sprinkle the rock with blood"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 17:1-7",
    "id": "000185"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the priest have to do with the blood of the guilt offering?",
    "correctAnswer": "Put it on the horns of the altar",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Put it on the ark",
      "Put it on the west side of the sanctuary of the holy ones",
      "Mix it with incense"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 29:12",
    "id": "000186"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did God say to Moses from the burning bush?",
    "correctAnswer": "I am the God of your fathers",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis",
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Go to Nineveh",
      "You are chosen above all nations",
      "I am your God"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 3:6",
    "id": "000187"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Noah build first after the flood?",
    "correctAnswer": "An altar",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A city",
      "A ship",
      "A tower"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 8:20",
    "id": "000188"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did God say to the serpent after the fall of Adam and Eve?",
    "correctAnswer": "\"Cursed are you above all livestock\"",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "\"You shall return to dust\"",
      "\"You shall leave your wife\"",
      "\"I will be gracious to you\""
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 3:14",
    "id": "000189"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the disciple Matthew first?",
    "correctAnswer": "Levi",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Simon",
      "Mark",
      "Lazarus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 9:9",
    "id": "000190"
  },
  {
    "question": "With whom did Mary, the mother of the Lord Jesus, live after Jesus' death?",
    "correctAnswer": "With John",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "With Martha",
      "With Peter",
      "With her sister"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "John 19: 26, 27",
    "id": "000191"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the Lord Jesus led by the Spirit after his baptism in the Jordan?",
    "correctAnswer": "Into the wilderness",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "To Galilee",
      "To Capernaum",
      "To his disciples"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 4 : 1-3",
    "id": "000192"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the Sermon on the Mount begin in Matthew 5?",
    "correctAnswer": "With the Beatitudes",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "With the Lord's Prayer",
      "With the parables of the seed",
      "With the commandment of love"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5: 1-12",
    "id": "000193"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first miracle of Jesus, mentioned in the biblical book of Mark?",
    "correctAnswer": "Casting out an unclean spirit",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Mark",
      "Luke"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Turning water into wine",
      "Peter walks on the water",
      "Jesus calms the storm"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1:21-28",
    "id": "000194"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is first mentioned in Matthew in the genealogy of Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abraham",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jacob",
      "Adam",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 1:1",
    "id": "000195"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first message that Jesus preached in Mark 1?",
    "correctAnswer": "Repent and believe the Gospel",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Love one another",
      "Go into the whole world",
      "Watch and pray"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1:15",
    "id": "000196"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom is the Gospel of Luke addressed?",
    "correctAnswer": "Theophilus",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Luke"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Timothy",
      "Titus",
      "Silas"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 1:3",
    "id": "000197"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who saw Jesus first after His resurrection?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Emmaus travelers",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Luke"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "Mary Magdalene",
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 24:15",
    "id": "000198"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the biblical book of Luke end?",
    "correctAnswer": "At the ascension of Jesus",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "At the crucifixion",
      "At Pentecost in Jerusalem",
      "At the announcement of the second coming"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 24: 50-53",
    "id": "000199"
  },
  {
    "question": "With what words does John 1 begin?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the beginning was the Word",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In the beginning God created",
      "And it came to pass",
      "This is the book of generations"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "John 1: 1",
    "id": "000200"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the woman at the well?",
    "correctAnswer": "A Samaritan woman",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A Jewess",
      "A Roman woman",
      "A Philistine woman"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "John 4:7",
    "id": "000201"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who took the place of Judas as apostle?",
    "correctAnswer": "Matthias",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Barnabas",
      "Paul",
      "Silas"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1: 15-26",
    "id": "000202"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Peter do after Pentecost?",
    "correctAnswer": "He preached",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He was silent",
      "He prayed in silence",
      "He fled"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 2:14-41",
    "id": "000203"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who converted on the road to Damascus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Saul",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "Barnabas",
      "Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 9: 1-6",
    "id": "000204"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the book of Acts end?",
    "correctAnswer": "With Paul's stay in Rome",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "With Paul's death",
      "With the destruction of Jerusalem",
      "With Pentecost"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 28",
    "id": "000205"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Paul describe himself in Romans 1:1?",
    "correctAnswer": "A servant of Jesus Christ",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A prophet of Jesus Christ",
      "A servant of men",
      "An apostle of John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 1:1",
    "id": "000206"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who are the true children of Abraham?",
    "correctAnswer": "Those who are of faith",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Those who are of the Spirit",
      "Those born in Israel",
      "Those who are of the flesh"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 4:16",
    "id": "000207"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul say that we must do with our bodies?",
    "correctAnswer": "Present them as a living, holy and pleasing sacrifice to God",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Subject them to the law",
      "Use them for good works",
      "Offer them as sacrifices"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 12: 1",
    "id": "000208"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of the law?",
    "correctAnswer": "Love",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Faith",
      "Obedience",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 13: 8-14",
    "id": "000209"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the problem in the church at Corinth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Strife and division",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Corinthians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Persecution",
      "Lack of faith",
      "Lack of love"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Corinthians 1:10-13",
    "id": "000210"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the body of a believer?",
    "correctAnswer": "A temple of the Holy Spirit",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Corinthians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Dust of the earth",
      "A sinful vessel",
      "A temporary tent"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Corinthians 6 and 20",
    "id": "000211"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many letters did Paul write to the Corinthians that have been preserved?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Corinthians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000212"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul say about weakness?",
    "correctAnswer": "My power is made perfect in weakness",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Corinthians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Weakness is a sin",
      "Avoid weakness at all times",
      "Faith overcomes weakness"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Corinthians 12:9",
    "id": "000213"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ministry that God has given to us?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ministry of reconciliation",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Corinthians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ministry of judgment",
      "Ministry of grace",
      "Ministry of the commandments"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Corinthians 5:18",
    "id": "000214"
  },
  {
    "question": "What surprises Paul?",
    "correctAnswer": "That they quickly turn to another gospel",
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "That the Galatians are devout",
      "That they fast much",
      "That they pray much"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 1:6",
    "id": "000215"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul say about the law?",
    "correctAnswer": "It is a tutor to Christ",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "It justifies",
      "It leads away from sins",
      "It is fulfilled in Christ"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 3:24",
    "id": "000216"
  },
  {
    "question": "Through what are we made righteous?",
    "correctAnswer": "Through faith, by grace",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Through the works of the law",
      "Through keeping the law",
      "Through prayer and fasting"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 2:16",
    "id": "000217"
  },
  {
    "question": "What must children do?",
    "correctAnswer": "Be obedient to their parents",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Be silent",
      "Work",
      "Pray"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 6:1-3",
    "id": "000218"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is life for Paul?",
    "correctAnswer": "Christ",
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Philippians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Suffering",
      "Struggle",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philippians 1:21",
    "id": "000219"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is mentioned as Paul's brother and fellow worker?",
    "correctAnswer": "Epaphroditus",
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Philippians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Barnabas",
      "Silas",
      "Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philippians 2:25",
    "id": "000220"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the letter to the Colossians?",
    "correctAnswer": "Paul",
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Colossians"
    ],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Colossians",
      "Silas",
      "Timotheus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians 1:1-2",
    "id": "000221"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the letter to the Thessalonians?",
    "correctAnswer": "Paul, Silvanus and Timothy",
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "Paul and Timothy",
      "Paul and Barnabas"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Thessalonians 1:1",
    "id": "000222"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Christ do that it was done?",
    "correctAnswer": "The angel of the Lord",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Moses",
      "The angel of the Lord",
      "The Holy Spirit"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Colossians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians 1:15",
    "id": "000223"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens to the dead in Christ at His coming?",
    "correctAnswer": "They shall rise first",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "They shall be judged",
      "They return with Jesus",
      "They shall rise last"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Thessalonians 4:16",
    "id": "000224"
  },
  {
    "question": "What must happen first before the day of the Lord comes?",
    "correctAnswer": "The falling away from the faith and the revealing of the man of sin",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The coming",
      "The resurrection from the dead",
      "The oppression"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Thessalonians 2",
    "id": "000225"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the \"man of sin\" also called?",
    "correctAnswer": "The son of perdition",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The antichrist",
      "The dragon",
      "The ruler of darkness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Thessalonians 2:3",
    "id": "000226"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Paul's blessing at the end of Thessalonians?",
    "correctAnswer": "The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you all. Amen.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Grace and peace be with you all. Amen.",
      "The love of God and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with you all, Amen.",
      "The peace of God be with you all. Amen."
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Thessalonians 3:18",
    "id": "000227"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul say about women in the worship service?",
    "correctAnswer": "That they should be in silence",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "That they should prophesy",
      "That they should teach the people",
      "That they should preach to the people"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Timothy 2:11",
    "id": "000228"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is God not?",
    "correctAnswer": "A spirit of fear",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A consuming fire",
      "A God of judgment",
      "A God of strife"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Timothy 1:7",
    "id": "000229"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which parable does Paul use for the life of a believer?",
    "correctAnswer": "Soldier, athlete, farmer",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Prophet, priest, king",
      "Redemption, pilgrimage, traveler",
      "Fisherman, farmer, soldier"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Timothy 2",
    "id": "000230"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who has Paul left, having loved the present world?",
    "correctAnswer": "Demas",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Timothy"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Timothy 4:10",
    "id": "000231"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Titus have to do on Crete?",
    "correctAnswer": "Appoint elders in every city",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Convince the Romans",
      "Appoint deacons in every city",
      "Establish a church"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Titus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Titus 1:5",
    "id": "000232"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul say about the saving grace of God?",
    "correctAnswer": "It has appeared to all men",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "It has come to Israel",
      "It has come for the chosen ones",
      "It teaches us to know Christ through the law"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Titus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Titus 2:11",
    "id": "000233"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Onesimus?",
    "correctAnswer": "A runaway slave",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A Roman soldier",
      "An elder",
      "A deacon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Philemon"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philemon 1:16",
    "id": "000234"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Melchizedek?",
    "correctAnswer": "A priest without genealogy",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A priest from the line of David",
      "A descendant of Abraham",
      "A descendant of Moses"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Hebrews"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hebrews 7:3",
    "id": "000235"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who are mentioned in Hebrews 11 as examples of faith?",
    "correctAnswer": "Noah, Abraham, Moses",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David, Elijah, Isaiah",
      "John, Peter, Andrew",
      "Paul, Timothy, Titus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Hebrews"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hebrews 11",
    "id": "000236"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the origin of reconciliation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Self-will",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The devil",
      "The self-will",
      "The world"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "James"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "James 1:14",
    "id": "000237"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who must pray for the sick?",
    "correctAnswer": "The elders of the church",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The deacons of the church",
      "The preachers of the church",
      "The believing physicians from the church"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "James"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "James 5:14-15",
    "id": "000238"
  },
  {
    "question": "God created the heaven and earth in six days",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2:2",
    "id": "000239"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cain killed his brother Abel",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 4:8",
    "id": "000240"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aaron was the father of Moses",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 6:19",
    "id": "000241"
  },
  {
    "question": "The law of the jubilee year is set out in Leviticus",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 25: 8-55",
    "id": "000242"
  },
  {
    "question": "Leviticus is primarily addressed to the tribe of Judah",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus",
    "id": "000243"
  },
  {
    "question": "Balaam's donkey spoke to him",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 22:28",
    "id": "000244"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deuteronomy means \"restoration of the law\"",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy",
    "id": "000245"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deuteronomy describes Moses' last speech",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 32 and 33",
    "id": "000246"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joshua was the nephew of Nun",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 1:1",
    "id": "000247"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sun stood still during a battle under Joshua's leadership",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 10:12-14",
    "id": "000248"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book Joshua ends with the death of Moses",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 24",
    "id": "000249"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book Judges ends with the words: 'In those days there was no king in Israel, everyone did what was right in his eyes'",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 21",
    "id": "000250"
  },
  {
    "question": "Samson was a judge in Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 13",
    "id": "000251"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ruth became the grandmother of King Solomon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4",
    "id": "000252"
  },
  {
    "question": "Samuel was raised in the holiness in Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:3",
    "id": "000253"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul was the first king of Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000254"
  },
  {
    "question": "Uzzah died when he touched the ark of God",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 6:6, 7",
    "id": "000255"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absalom, David's son, rose in rebellion against David",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 13 - 18",
    "id": "000256"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elijah slaughtered the Baal priests on Mount Carmel",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 18",
    "id": "000257"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Solomon the kingdom remained intact",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 12",
    "id": "000258"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elisha received a double portion of Elijah's spirit",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 2:9, 10",
    "id": "000259"
  },
  {
    "question": "David brought the ark to Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 15",
    "id": "000260"
  },
  {
    "question": "David built the temple in Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 2:1",
    "id": "000261"
  },
  {
    "question": "Josiah found the book of the law in the temple",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 34",
    "id": "000262"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cyrus was the king of the Medes",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 1:1",
    "id": "000263"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezra led the first group of exiles back to Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 2:1, 2",
    "id": "000264"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezra was a priest and scribe",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 7:6, 11",
    "id": "000265"
  },
  {
    "question": "The temple was rebuilt during the time of Ezra",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 5 and 6",
    "id": "000266"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rebuilding of the temple was never completed",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 4: 1-5",
    "id": "000267"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nehemiah was cupbearer to the court of the king of Babylon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nehemiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 1:11",
    "id": "000268"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nehemiah led the rebuilding of the walls of Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nehemiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 2 and 18",
    "id": "000269"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mordecai was the father of Esther",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Esther"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 2:7",
    "id": "000270"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book Esther never mentions the name of God",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Esther"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 1",
    "id": "000271"
  },
  {
    "question": "Job was a rich man from the land of Uz",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 1:1",
    "id": "000272"
  },
  {
    "question": "The wife of Job said: 'Bless God and die'",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 2:9",
    "id": "000273"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Psalms contain both praises and complaints",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms",
    "id": "000274"
  },
  {
    "question": "David was the writer of the Biblical book Psalms",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms",
    "id": "000275"
  },
  {
    "question": "Solomon is the most important writer of the Biblical book Proverbs",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:1",
    "id": "000276"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wickedness does the monkey tricks",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs",
    "id": "000277"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prophet is addressed to Solomon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:1 and 12",
    "id": "000278"
  },
  {
    "question": "False teachers are deceiving",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs",
    "id": "000279"
  },
  {
    "question": "The king has made a chariot of wood from Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Haggai"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 3:9",
    "id": "000280"
  },
  {
    "question": "Draw me, we will leave you",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Haggai"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 1:4",
    "id": "000281"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isaiah prophesied about the coming of the Messiah",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 7, 9, 11, 53",
    "id": "000282"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Bible Isaiah has 66 chapters",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 66",
    "id": "000283"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeremiah wrote a book to the exiles in Babylon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 29:1",
    "id": "000284"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeremiah says: Ah, LORD GOD, behold, I cannot speak",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 1:6",
    "id": "000285"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lamentations was written after the destruction of Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Lamentations"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Lamentations 1",
    "id": "000286"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Lamentations comes no single hope for you",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Lamentations"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Lamentations 3: 21-23",
    "id": "000287"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel prophesied in Babylon, went from Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 1:1-3",
    "id": "000288"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel ends with: and I was already there",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35",
    "id": "000289"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniel worked at the court of former kings in Babylon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel",
    "id": "000290"
  },
  {
    "question": "King Nebuchadnezzar made a statue of gold, the height was 60 cubits",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 3:1",
    "id": "000291"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hosea called the people to return to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 6:1",
    "id": "000292"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hosea preached only about love and forgiveness",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea",
    "id": "000293"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joel describes a plague as judgment",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 1",
    "id": "000294"
  },
  {
    "question": "Egypt and Edom will be saved, despite that they have turned against God",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 3:19",
    "id": "000295"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amos was a shepherd from Tekoa",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Amos"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Amos 1:1",
    "id": "000296"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amos saw in a vision a basket of summer fruit",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Amos"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Amos 8:1",
    "id": "000297"
  },
  {
    "question": "Obadiah is the shortest Bible book from the Old Testament",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Obadiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Obadiah 1",
    "id": "000298"
  },
  {
    "question": "Obadiah's prophecy is directed against Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Obadiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Obadiah 1:1",
    "id": "000299"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jonah was happy with God's compassion for Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jonah 4",
    "id": "000300"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jonah was swallowed by God to go to Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jonah 1:2",
    "id": "000301"
  },
  {
    "question": "Micah foretold the birthplace of the Messiah",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Micah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Micah 5:1",
    "id": "000302"
  },
  {
    "question": "Micah lived in the time of King Ahab",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Micah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Micah 1:1",
    "id": "000303"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nahum prophesied against the city Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nahum"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nahum 1, 2, 3",
    "id": "000304"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Nahum it says: four your times, O Jerusalem, pay your vows",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nahum"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nahum",
    "id": "000305"
  },
  {
    "question": "Habakkuk says: \"the righteous shall live by his faith\"",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Habakkuk"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Habakkuk 2:4",
    "id": "000306"
  },
  {
    "question": "Habakkuk is shaken by God because of his doubts",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Habakkuk"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Habakkuk",
    "id": "000307"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zephaniah prophesied about the overthrow of Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Zephaniah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Zephaniah 1",
    "id": "000308"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Zephaniah comes no single hope for you",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Zephaniah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Zephaniah 3: 21-23",
    "id": "000309"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel prophesied in Babylon, went from Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 1:1-3",
    "id": "000310"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel ends with: and I was already there",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35",
    "id": "000311"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniel worked at the court of former kings in Babylon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel",
    "id": "000312"
  },
  {
    "question": "King Nebuchadnezzar made a statue of gold, the height was 60 cubits",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 3:1",
    "id": "000313"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hosea called the people to return to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 6:1",
    "id": "000314"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hosea preached only about love and forgiveness",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea",
    "id": "000315"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joel describes a plague as judgment",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 1",
    "id": "000316"
  },
  {
    "question": "Egypt and Edom will be saved, despite that they have turned against God",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Joel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 3:19",
    "id": "000317"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amos was a shepherd from Tekoa",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Amos"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Amos 1:1",
    "id": "000318"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amos saw in a vision a basket of summer fruit",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Amos"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Amos 8:1",
    "id": "000319"
  },
  {
    "question": "Obadiah is the shortest Bible book from the Old Testament",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Obadiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Obadiah 1",
    "id": "000320"
  },
  {
    "question": "Obadiah's prophecy is directed against Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Obadiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Obadiah 1:1",
    "id": "000321"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jonah was happy with God's compassion for Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jonah 4",
    "id": "000322"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jonah was swallowed by God to go to Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jonah 1:2",
    "id": "000323"
  },
  {
    "question": "Micah foretold the birthplace of the Messiah",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Micah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Micah 5:1",
    "id": "000324"
  },
  {
    "question": "Micah lived in the time of King Ahab",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Micah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Micah 1:1",
    "id": "000325"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nahum prophesied against the city Nineveh",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nahum"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nahum 1, 2, 3",
    "id": "000326"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Nahum it says: four your times, O Jerusalem, pay your vows",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Nahum"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nahum",
    "id": "000327"
  },
  {
    "question": "Habakkuk says: \"the righteous shall live by his faith\"",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Habakkuk"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Habakkuk 2:4",
    "id": "000328"
  },
  {
    "question": "Habakkuk is shaken by God because of his doubts",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Habakkuk"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Habakkuk",
    "id": "000329"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zephaniah prophesied about the overthrow of Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Zephaniah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Zephaniah 1",
    "id": "000330"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zephaniah was written after the destruction of Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Zephaniah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Zephaniah 1",
    "id": "000331"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel prophesied in Babylon, went from Jerusalem",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 1:1-3",
    "id": "000332"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel ends with: and I was already there",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35",
    "id": "000333"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniel worked at the court of former kings in Babylon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel",
    "id": "000334"
  },
  {
    "question": "King Nebuchadnezzar made a statue of gold, the height was 60 cubits",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 3:1",
    "id": "000335"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul mentions the fruits of the Spirit in Galatians",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 5:22",
    "id": "000336"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Christ there is difference between Jew and Greek, Paul writes in Galatians",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 3:28",
    "id": "000337"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Ephesians the spiritual armor is described",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 6: 10-20",
    "id": "000338"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul wrote the biblical book Ephesians during his first missionary journey",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians",
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 3:1",
    "id": "000339"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philippians is addressed to the Christians in Philippi",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Philippians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philippians",
    "id": "000340"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Philippians it says \"For to me to live is Christ, and to die is gain\"",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Philippians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philippians 1:21",
    "id": "000341"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Colossians the fruits of the Spirit are described",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians",
    "id": "000342"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul knew the Christians of Colossae personally",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Colossians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians 1",
    "id": "000343"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Thessalonians is probably Paul's oldest letter",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Thessalonians",
    "id": "000344"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Thessalonians Paul calls to holy walk and brotherly love",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Thessalonians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Thessalonians 4",
    "id": "000345"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Thessalonians Paul calls to steadfastness",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Thessalonians 2: 13-17",
    "id": "000346"
  },
  {
    "question": "2 Thessalonians is mainly a repetition of the first letter",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Thessalonians",
    "id": "000347"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes in 1 Timothy about the office of elders and deacons",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Timothy 3",
    "id": "000348"
  },
  {
    "question": "Timothy was a pastor in Rome",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Timothy",
    "id": "000349"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes in 1 Timothy about the role of women in the church",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Timothy",
    "id": "000350"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Timothy Paul mentions \"All Scripture is God-breathed\"",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Timothy 3:16",
    "id": "000351"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Timothy Paul expects that he will go on a journey soon",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "1 Timothy",
      "2 Timothy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Timothy",
    "id": "000352"
  },
  {
    "question": "Titus was left by Paul on the island of Cyprus",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Philemon"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Titus 1:5",
    "id": "000353"
  },
  {
    "question": "Titus contains instructions for appointing elders",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Philemon",
      "Titus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Titus 1: 5-9",
    "id": "000354"
  },
  {
    "question": "When ... saw that she was not bearing children for Jacob, she envied ... her sister.",
    "correctAnswer": "Rachel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Leah",
      "Bilhah",
      "Zilpah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 30:1",
    "id": "000355"
  },
  {
    "question": "And Adam lived ... years and begot a son in his own likeness, in his own image, and named his name Seth",
    "correctAnswer": "130",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "90",
      "110",
      "140"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 5:3",
    "id": "000356"
  },
  {
    "question": "So all the days of Enoch were ... years",
    "correctAnswer": "365",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "969",
      "300",
      "782"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 5:23",
    "id": "000357"
  },
  {
    "question": "But Noah found ... in the eyes of the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "grace",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "mercy",
      "forgiveness",
      "goodness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 6:8",
    "id": "000358"
  },
  {
    "question": "And the Lord said: Shall I hide from ... what I do?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abraham",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Adam",
      "Noah",
      "Lot"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 18:17",
    "id": "000359"
  },
  {
    "question": "Moses led the people out of ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Egypt",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Babylon",
      "Canaan",
      "Assyria"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 12",
    "id": "000360"
  },
  {
    "question": "The law was given on the mountain ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Sinai",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Horeb",
      "Nebo",
      "Moria"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 19 and 20",
    "id": "000361"
  },
  {
    "question": "And they shall make Me a ... that I may dwell in their midst",
    "correctAnswer": "sanctuary",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "tent",
      "tabernacle",
      "temple"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 25:8",
    "id": "000362"
  },
  {
    "question": "His snuffers and his ... shall be pure gold",
    "correctAnswer": "snuff dishes",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "lamps",
      "knops",
      "tongs"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 25:38",
    "id": "000363"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then he (Moses) said: Show me Your ...",
    "correctAnswer": "glory",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "goodness",
      "grace",
      "greatness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 33:18",
    "id": "000364"
  },
  {
    "question": "Break them in pieces and pour oil on it: it is a ...",
    "correctAnswer": "grain offering",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "burnt offering",
      "fire offering",
      "thanksgiving offering"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 2:6",
    "id": "000365"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a ... ; he has certainly made himself guilty to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "guilt offering",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "burnt offering",
      "thanksgiving offering",
      "peace offering"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 5:19",
    "id": "000366"
  },
  {
    "question": "And the priest shall light it on the altar as burnt offering to the Lord; it is a ...",
    "correctAnswer": "guilt offering",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "sin offering",
      "burnt offering",
      "thanksgiving offering"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 7:5",
    "id": "000367"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Moses heard that, it was ... in his eyes",
    "correctAnswer": "good",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "evil",
      "right",
      "beautiful"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 10:20",
    "id": "000368"
  },
  {
    "question": "Also the ... of that oil shall pour it on the priest's left hand",
    "correctAnswer": "priest",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "prophet",
      "man",
      "survivor"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Leviticus 14:26",
    "id": "000369"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Numbers begins with a census of the ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Israelites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "priests",
      "Levites",
      "foreigners"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 1",
    "id": "000370"
  },
  {
    "question": "Moses then spoke to the children of Israel, that they should keep the ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Passover",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "commandment",
      "feast of tabernacles",
      "faith"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus",
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 9:4",
    "id": "000371"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the tribe of Judah ..., the son of Jephunneh",
    "correctAnswer": "Caleb",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Simeon",
      "Issachar",
      "Benjamin"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 13:6",
    "id": "000372"
  },
  {
    "question": "And ... did it; as the Lord commanded him, so he did",
    "correctAnswer": "Moses",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Levi",
      "Edom"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 17:11",
    "id": "000373"
  },
  {
    "question": "But the children of ... did not die",
    "correctAnswer": "Korah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Dathan",
      "Abiram",
      "Eliab"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 26:11",
    "id": "000374"
  },
  {
    "question": "Moses spoke to the people before they entered the promised land ...",
    "correctAnswer": "entered",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "left",
      "conquered",
      "forgot"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus",
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 1",
    "id": "000375"
  },
  {
    "question": "Moses died on the mountain ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Nebo",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sinai",
      "Horeb",
      "Hor"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus",
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 34:5",
    "id": "000376"
  },
  {
    "question": "Therefore the Lord has said to me: You shall not cross this ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Jordan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Land",
      "River",
      "Mountain"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 3:27",
    "id": "000377"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ... you shall not muzzle, when he is thirsty",
    "correctAnswer": "ox",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "bull",
      "ram",
      "bear"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 25:4",
    "id": "000378"
  },
  {
    "question": "For you shall do what ... is in the eyes of the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "right",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "good",
      "evil",
      "just"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Deuteronomy 12:28",
    "id": "000379"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then Joshua commanded the ... of the people, saying:",
    "correctAnswer": "officers",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "leaders",
      "heads",
      "sons"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua",
    "id": "000380"
  },
  {
    "question": "And He said: No, but I am the ... of the host of the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "Commander",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "King",
      "Priest",
      "Prophet"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 5",
    "id": "000381"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then Joshua built an altar to the Lord, the God of Israel, on the mountain ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Ebal",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Horeb",
      "Sinai",
      "Hermon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 8:30",
    "id": "000382"
  },
  {
    "question": "But the king of ... they captured alive, and they brought him to Joshua",
    "correctAnswer": "Ai",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lebanon",
      "Perez",
      "Gibeon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 8:23",
    "id": "000383"
  },
  {
    "question": "Those five kings were found, hidden in the cave at ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Makkedah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Adullam",
      "Machpelah",
      "the prophets"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 10:16",
    "id": "000384"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first judge of Israel was ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Othniel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ehud",
      "Shamgar",
      "Gideon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3",
    "id": "000385"
  },
  {
    "question": "... now, a woman who was a prophetess, the wife of Lappidoth",
    "correctAnswer": "Deborah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rebekah",
      "Jael",
      "Priscilla"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 4:4",
    "id": "000386"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gideon asked for a sign from God with a ...",
    "correctAnswer": "fleece of wool",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "dream",
      "vision",
      "voice"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 6:37",
    "id": "000387"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then the trees said to the vine: Come you, be ... over us",
    "correctAnswer": "king",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "ruler",
      "prince",
      "chief"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ecclesiastes"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 9:12",
    "id": "000388"
  },
  {
    "question": "And ... vowed a vow to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "Jephthah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jair",
      "Gideon",
      "Ephraim"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 11",
    "id": "000389"
  },
  {
    "question": "And ..., the husband of Naomi died",
    "correctAnswer": "Elimelech",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Mahlon",
      "Chilion",
      "Boaz"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis",
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:3",
    "id": "000390"
  },
  {
    "question": "Call me not Naomi, call me ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Mara",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Orpah",
      "Ruth",
      "Rachel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:20",
    "id": "000391"
  },
  {
    "question": "Naomi now had a kinsman of her husband, a man, mighty in ...",
    "correctAnswer": "wealth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "name",
      "spirit",
      "goodness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 2:1",
    "id": "000392"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lord will reward your ..., and your reward will be full from the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "deed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "wage",
      "goodness",
      "faith"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 2:12",
    "id": "000393"
  },
  {
    "question": "When she now rose ...",
    "correctAnswer": "to read",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "to go",
      "to work",
      "to comfort her"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth",
    "id": "000394"
  },
  {
    "question": "And she said to her: All what you ... , I will do",
    "correctAnswer": "say to me",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "command me",
      "threaten me",
      "speak to me"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth",
    "id": "000395"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elkanah went annually to sacrifice in ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Shiloh",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "the temple",
      "the tabernacle"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:3",
    "id": "000396"
  },
  {
    "question": "But when a man sins against the Lord, who will ...",
    "correctAnswer": "pray for him",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "be able to exist",
      "still seek",
      "then find"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 2:25",
    "id": "000397"
  },
  {
    "question": "And I will raise up for Myself a ... priest, who will do as is in My heart and in My soul shall be",
    "correctAnswer": "faithful",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "man",
      "prophet",
      "son"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 2:35",
    "id": "000398"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul became jealous of David because he ...",
    "correctAnswer": "received more praise",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "had more wealth",
      "had more friends",
      "possessed more land"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 18",
    "id": "000399"
  },
  {
    "question": "David became king over Israel in the city ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Hebron",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Jericho"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 2",
    "id": "000400"
  },
  {
    "question": "David brought the ark of God to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Jerusalem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Bethel",
      "Hebron",
      "Gilgal"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 6",
    "id": "000401"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lord sent the prophet ... to David",
    "correctAnswer": "Nathan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Elijah",
      "Elisha",
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 12:1",
    "id": "000402"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absalom fled to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Geshur",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Rabbah",
      "Ziklag"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 13:38",
    "id": "000403"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which woman said: Keep the king?",
    "correctAnswer": "the Tekoite",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the Ammonitess",
      "the Hittite",
      "the Israelitess"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel",
    "id": "000404"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wanted to become king when David was old?",
    "correctAnswer": "Adonijah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Solomon",
      "Joab",
      "Absalom"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 1",
    "id": "000405"
  },
  {
    "question": "Grant me ... , the priest",
    "correctAnswer": "Zadok",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Nathan",
      "Benaiah",
      "Joiada"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 1:32",
    "id": "000406"
  },
  {
    "question": "and they have made him ride on ... of the king",
    "correctAnswer": "the mule",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the donkey",
      "the chariot",
      "the horse"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Christ"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 1",
    "id": "000407"
  },
  {
    "question": "I go in the way of all the earth; so you are strong and become ...",
    "correctAnswer": "a man",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "brave",
      "a watchman",
      "God-fearing"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 2:2",
    "id": "000408"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apply your ... so that you do not let her gray hair descend with peace into the grave",
    "correctAnswer": "wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "word",
      "understanding",
      "wealth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ecclesiastes"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 2:6",
    "id": "000409"
  },
  {
    "question": "The king of Israel in time of Elisha was ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Joram",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ahab",
      "Solomon",
      "David"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 3",
    "id": "000410"
  },
  {
    "question": "He then said to the young men: ... him to his mother",
    "correctAnswer": "bring",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "carry",
      "lead",
      "give"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 4:27",
    "id": "000411"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Elisha then returned to ..., there was famine in that land",
    "correctAnswer": "Gilgal",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Shunem",
      "Baal-shalisha",
      "Syria"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 4:38",
    "id": "000412"
  },
  {
    "question": "His ... and ..., the rivers of Damascus, are better than all waters of Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "Abana, Pharpar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Euphrates, Tigris",
      "Pison, Gihon",
      "Jordan, Nile"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 5:12",
    "id": "000413"
  },
  {
    "question": "that the iron fell in the water, and he cried and said: Ah, my lord; for it was ...",
    "correctAnswer": "heavy",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "fallen",
      "broken",
      "rusty"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 6:5",
    "id": "000414"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Chronicles begins with a list of ...",
    "correctAnswer": "generations",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "kings",
      "prophets",
      "priests"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 1",
    "id": "000415"
  },
  {
    "question": "and his mother had called him ..., saying: For I bore him with pain",
    "correctAnswer": "Jabez",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Perez",
      "Hezron",
      "Etam"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 4:9",
    "id": "000416"
  },
  {
    "question": "And in days of Saul they fought against the ... ; who fell by their hand",
    "correctAnswer": "Hagarites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Gadites",
      "Reubenites",
      "Hivites"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 5:10",
    "id": "000417"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aaron now and his sons burned offerings on the altar of ... and on the incense altar",
    "correctAnswer": "burnt offerings",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "grain offerings",
      "sin offerings",
      "thanksgiving offerings"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 6:49",
    "id": "000418"
  },
  {
    "question": "So Saul and his ... died",
    "correctAnswer": "three",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "two",
      "four",
      "five"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 10:13",
    "id": "000419"
  },
  {
    "question": "Solomon built a temple in Jerusalem on the mountain ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Moria",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sinai",
      "Carmel",
      "Zion"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 3:1",
    "id": "000420"
  },
  {
    "question": "The king who restored the temple was ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Josiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Solomon",
      "Ahaz"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Chronicles",
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 34",
    "id": "000421"
  },
  {
    "question": "and he called the name of judge ... and of the left Boaz",
    "correctAnswer": "Jachin",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Joachin",
      "Jacob",
      "Jehozadak"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 3:17",
    "id": "000422"
  },
  {
    "question": "And they brought for Solomon ... from Egypt and from all those lands",
    "correctAnswer": "horses",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "gold",
      "silver",
      "camels"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles 1:17",
    "id": "000423"
  },
  {
    "question": "And Solomon reigned in Jerusalem over all Israel ... years",
    "correctAnswer": "40",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "30",
      "34",
      "45"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Chronicles",
    "id": "000424"
  },
  {
    "question": "The return of the exiles began under king ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyrus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Darius",
      "Nebuchadnezzar",
      "Xerxes"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra",
    "id": "000425"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezra led the return of the Israelites to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Jerusalem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Egypt",
      "Babylon",
      "Moab"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra",
    "id": "000426"
  },
  {
    "question": "And they set up the Levites from ... years old and above to take oversight over work of Lord's house",
    "correctAnswer": "18",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "20",
      "22",
      "25"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 3:8",
    "id": "000427"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letter which you have fitted for us, is ... for me to read",
    "correctAnswer": "profitable",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "unprofitable",
      "good",
      "readable"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Philemon"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 4:18",
    "id": "000428"
  },
  {
    "question": "Now when I fast at the river ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Ahava",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Tigris",
      "Euphrates",
      "Pison"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezra 8:21",
    "id": "000429"
  },
  {
    "question": "I now was ... of the king",
    "correctAnswer": "cupbearer",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "baker",
      "priest",
      "prophet"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 1:11",
    "id": "000430"
  },
  {
    "question": "The walls of Jerusalem were rebuilt in ... days",
    "correctAnswer": "52",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "42",
      "30",
      "70"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezra",
      "Nehemiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 6:15",
    "id": "000431"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nehemiah was concerned over the ... of the people",
    "correctAnswer": "sins",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "wealth",
      "diseases",
      "gave"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Nehemiah",
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 1: 6,7",
    "id": "000432"
  },
  {
    "question": "Remember me, my God, for good, all that I have ... to this people",
    "correctAnswer": "done for",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "done to You",
      "done to them",
      "done to these"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 5:19",
    "id": "000433"
  },
  {
    "question": "Come and let us gather together in the valleys, in the valley ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Ono",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ela",
      "Kison",
      "Hinnom"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Nehemiah 6:2",
    "id": "000434"
  },
  {
    "question": "Esther was ..., beautiful and lovely in form",
    "correctAnswer": "white",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "black",
      "yellow",
      "red"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 1:1",
    "id": "000435"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the twelfth month, which is the month ..., in the tenth year of his reign",
    "correctAnswer": "Tebeth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Nisan",
      "Sivan",
      "Adar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 2:16",
    "id": "000436"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then Esther called ..., one of the king's chamberlains",
    "correctAnswer": "Hatach",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Haman",
      "Heber",
      "Hanan"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Esther"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 4:5",
    "id": "000437"
  },
  {
    "question": "With the Jews there was light and joy and ...",
    "correctAnswer": "gladness",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "honor",
      "praise",
      "happiness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 8:16",
    "id": "000438"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the Jews were light and gladness and ...",
    "correctAnswer": "glory",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "honor",
      "praise",
      "happiness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Esther 8:16",
    "id": "000439"
  },
  {
    "question": "And to him were born ... sons and three daughters",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "5",
      "8",
      "3"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 1:2",
    "id": "000440"
  },
  {
    "question": "In all this Job did not sin, and charged God with nothing ...",
    "correctAnswer": "unrighteous",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "wrong",
      "evil",
      "good"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 1:22",
    "id": "000441"
  },
  {
    "question": "For He gives pain and He ...; He wounds and His hands heal",
    "correctAnswer": "binds",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "heals",
      "creates",
      "helps"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Christ",
      "Psalm"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 5:18",
    "id": "000442"
  },
  {
    "question": "Teach me, and I will ... and will give me understanding in which I erred",
    "correctAnswer": "keep silent",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "preach",
      "go",
      "walk"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 6:24",
    "id": "000443"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then answered ..., the Shuhite, and said:",
    "correctAnswer": "Bildad",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Eliphaz",
      "Zophar",
      "Elihu"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 25:1",
    "id": "000444"
  },
  {
    "question": "Serves the Lord with ..., and pleases Him with thanksgiving",
    "correctAnswer": "fear",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "joy",
      "gladness",
      "honor"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 2:11",
    "id": "000445"
  },
  {
    "question": "I lay down and slept; I was ashamed, for the Lord ... me",
    "correctAnswer": "sustained",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "helped",
      "redeemed",
      "honored"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 3:6",
    "id": "000446"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lord has heard my ...; the Lord will accept my prayer",
    "correctAnswer": "crying",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "prayer",
      "song",
      "praise"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 6:10",
    "id": "000447"
  },
  {
    "question": "O Lord, our Lord, how ... is Your Name in all the earth",
    "correctAnswer": "glorious",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "big",
      "heavenly",
      "lovely"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 8:10",
    "id": "000448"
  },
  {
    "question": "Therefore I will praise You, O Lord, among the heathen, and I will ... Your name",
    "correctAnswer": "sing psalms to",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "love",
      "bless",
      "praise"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalms 18:50",
    "id": "000449"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fear of the Lord is the beginning of ...",
    "correctAnswer": "wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "wisdom",
      "joy",
      "blessedness"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms",
      "Proverbs",
      "Ecclesiastes",
      "Haggai"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:7",
    "id": "000450"
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you seek her as silver and consume her like ...",
    "correctAnswer": "hidden treasures",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "wealth",
      "possessions",
      "gold"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 2:4",
    "id": "000451"
  },
  {
    "question": "Trust in the Lord with your whole heart, and lean not on your ...",
    "correctAnswer": "understanding",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "heart",
      "wealth",
      "knowledge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms",
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3:5",
    "id": "000452"
  },
  {
    "question": "I will instruct you in the path of ...; I will make my eyes on your ways",
    "correctAnswer": "wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "good",
      "straight",
      "level"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:11",
    "id": "000453"
  },
  {
    "question": "Commit your ... to the Lord, and your thoughts will be established",
    "correctAnswer": "works",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "way",
      "thoughts",
      "eyes"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 16:3",
    "id": "000454"
  },
  {
    "question": "All has a ... time",
    "correctAnswer": "destined time",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "fixed",
      "good",
      "set time"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ecclesiastes"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ecclesiastes 3:1",
    "id": "000455"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Ecclesiastes is written to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Solomon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Moses",
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ecclesiastes"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ecclesiastes 1:1",
    "id": "000456"
  },
  {
    "question": "And it has neither seen ... nor known it; it has more rest than he",
    "correctAnswer": "sun",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "moon",
      "stars",
      "waters"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ecclesiastes"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ecclesiastes 6:5",
    "id": "000457"
  },
  {
    "question": "and who breaks a ... through will be caught by him",
    "correctAnswer": "hedge",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "lizard",
      "mouse",
      "weasel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 10:8",
    "id": "000458"
  },
  {
    "question": "and much reading is wearing out of ...",
    "correctAnswer": "flesh",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "understanding",
      "eyes",
      "vision"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 12:12",
    "id": "000459"
  },
  {
    "question": "Draw me, we will ...",
    "correctAnswer": "open up",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "find",
      "approach",
      "seek"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Haggai"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 1:4",
    "id": "000460"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bars of our houses are ...",
    "correctAnswer": "cedars",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "oaks",
      "from olive wood",
      "from acacia wood"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms",
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 1:17",
    "id": "000461"
  },
  {
    "question": "For behold, the ... is past",
    "correctAnswer": "winter",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "summer",
      "spring",
      "autumn"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 2:11",
    "id": "000462"
  },
  {
    "question": "When I knew it, I set My soul on the ... of My people",
    "correctAnswer": "violent",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "gentle",
      "loving",
      "restless"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 6:12",
    "id": "000463"
  },
  {
    "question": "Solomon had a daughter in ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Baal-Hamon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hamon",
      "Baal-Gad",
      "Jeroboam-Baal"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Haggai 8:11",
    "id": "000464"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ... will be gathered again, even to the God of heaven",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacob's",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah's",
      "Abraham's",
      "David's"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 10:21",
    "id": "000465"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ... and the ... shall come together",
    "correctAnswer": "cow, bear",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "lion",
      "wolf",
      "sheep"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 11:7",
    "id": "000466"
  },
  {
    "question": "Praising the Lord, for He has done ... things",
    "correctAnswer": "glorious",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "good",
      "Godly"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 12:5",
    "id": "000467"
  },
  {
    "question": "and the prophet Isaiah, the son of ..., came to him",
    "correctAnswer": "Amoz",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hezekiah",
      "Ahab",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 38:1",
    "id": "000468"
  },
  {
    "question": "O Zion, you who ... of good news",
    "correctAnswer": "bring forth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "hear",
      "proclaim",
      "publish"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 40:9",
    "id": "000469"
  },
  {
    "question": "And I said: Ah, Lord God, behold, I cannot speak, for I am ...",
    "correctAnswer": "young",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "old",
      "experienced",
      "ashamed"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 1:6",
    "id": "000470"
  },
  {
    "question": "for I am with you, to ... to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "plead",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "help",
      "support",
      "listen"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 1:8",
    "id": "000471"
  },
  {
    "question": "He will bring to them a ... who will be strong for them",
    "correctAnswer": "wind",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "storm",
      "rain",
      "overflow"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 4:12",
    "id": "000472"
  },
  {
    "question": "See, you trust on ... which do no good",
    "correctAnswer": "false words",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "gold",
      "thoughts",
      "teachers"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 7:8",
    "id": "000473"
  },
  {
    "question": "You set my ... to the days of sorrows",
    "correctAnswer": "remembrance",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "fear",
      "despair",
      "grief"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 17:17",
    "id": "000474"
  },
  {
    "question": "My soul is weary of ... and bows down within me",
    "correctAnswer": "life",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "living",
      "grief",
      "distress"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Klaagliederen 3:20",
    "id": "000475"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it ... of the Lord, that we have not been destroyed?",
    "correctAnswer": "kindnesses",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "goodnesses",
      "righteousnesses",
      "mercies"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Klaagliederen 3:22",
    "id": "000476"
  },
  {
    "question": "They are all ... tomorrow, Your love is great",
    "correctAnswer": "new",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "goodness",
      "faith",
      "loving"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Klaagliederen 3:23",
    "id": "000477"
  },
  {
    "question": "For he plots and deceives people children not ...",
    "correctAnswer": "from heart",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "with lust",
      "with malice",
      "in eternity"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Klaagliederen 3:33",
    "id": "000478"
  },
  {
    "question": "You have already seen ..., all their thoughts against me",
    "correctAnswer": "all",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "their evil",
      "their sins",
      "their plotting"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Klaagliederen 3:60",
    "id": "000479"
  },
  {
    "question": "And when I opened my mouth, and He gave me that role to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "eat",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "listen",
      "observe",
      "see"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 3:2",
    "id": "000480"
  },
  {
    "question": "Men, set your face against the ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Israel's mountains",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Cherubim",
      "around Jerusalem",
      "Zions"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 6:2",
    "id": "000481"
  },
  {
    "question": "And He said to me: Man, go now and walk in ...",
    "correctAnswer": "wilderness",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "earth",
      "mountains",
      "river"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 8:8",
    "id": "000482"
  },
  {
    "question": "And the inhabited places shall be ...",
    "correctAnswer": "ruins",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "destroyed",
      "abandoned",
      "overthrown"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 12:20",
    "id": "000483"
  },
  {
    "question": "But Noah, Daniel and ... were in the middle of it themselves",
    "correctAnswer": "Job",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Amos",
      "Jonah",
      "David"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 14:20",
    "id": "000484"
  },
  {
    "question": "and that men subdued them in the speech of the ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Chaldeans",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Babylonians",
      "Persians",
      "Egyptians"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 1:4",
    "id": "000485"
  },
  {
    "question": "and Daniel named him ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Belteshazzar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Shadrach",
      "Meshach",
      "Abed-nego"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 1:7",
    "id": "000486"
  },
  {
    "question": "Yet be patient, ..., your kingdom is divided",
    "correctAnswer": "10 days",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "6 days",
      "7 days",
      "14 days"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 1:12",
    "id": "000487"
  },
  {
    "question": "Then Daniel entered until ..., of the king who had set up the wise men of Babylon to bring us to eat and drink",
    "correctAnswer": "Arioch",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Melzar",
      "Shadrach",
      "Ari-el"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 2:24",
    "id": "000488"
  },
  {
    "question": "... , your kingdom is divided",
    "correctAnswer": "Medes",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Persians",
      "Greeks",
      "Tekei"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 5:28",
    "id": "000489"
  },
  {
    "question": "and in the days of ..., son of Joash, king of Israel",
    "correctAnswer": "Jeroboam",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jotham",
      "Ahaz",
      "Hezekiah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Kings",
      "1 Chronicles",
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 1:1",
    "id": "000490"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is not his name ...; for you have not been My people",
    "correctAnswer": "Lo-Ruhamah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lo-Ruchamah",
      "Lizreel",
      "Gomer"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 1:9",
    "id": "000491"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephraim is ..., let him go and become a ...",
    "correctAnswer": "godless",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "brother",
      "priest",
      "prophet"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 4:17",
    "id": "000492"
  },
  {
    "question": "Come and let us ... to the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "return",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "repent",
      "observe",
      "pray"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 6:1",
    "id": "000493"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is ...? Who understands these things",
    "correctAnswer": "wise",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "understanding",
      "right",
      "insightful"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 14:10",
    "id": "000494"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word of the Lord that has gone forth to ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Joel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Pethuel",
      "Jeremiah",
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 1:1",
    "id": "000495"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consecrate the ... to Zion",
    "correctAnswer": "Sion",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Jericho"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 2:1",
    "id": "000496"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fear not, O land; be ... and be glad",
    "correctAnswer": "joyful",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "peaceful",
      "thankful",
      "happy"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 2:21",
    "id": "000497"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is ... who calls you?",
    "correctAnswer": "He",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Heavenly Father",
      "Holy Spirit",
      "Lord God"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 2:32",
    "id": "000498"
  },
  {
    "question": "and everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be ...",
    "correctAnswer": "saved",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "blessed",
      "redeemed",
      "forgiven"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joel 2:32",
    "id": "000499"
  },
  {
    "question": "And ... shall become a wilderness and desolation",
    "correctAnswer": "Egypt",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Judah",
      "Edom",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 29:9",
    "id": "000499"
  },
  {
    "question": "that when that field is called in their own language ..., that is a field of blood",
    "correctAnswer": "Abel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Cain",
      "Achad",
      "Abeldam"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1:19",
    "id": "000500"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the father of Joseph, the man of Mary (Jesus' mother)?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacob",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Eliud",
      "Mattan",
      "Eleazar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 1:16",
    "id": "000501"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days and nights did Jesus fast in the wilderness?",
    "correctAnswer": "40",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7",
      "10",
      "30"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 4:2",
    "id": "000502"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus says the salt of the earth has lost its ... What does Jesus say happens to it?",
    "correctAnswer": "It is thrown out and trampled by people",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "It is blessed and salted",
      "It becomes purified",
      "Its taste changes pleasantly"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:13",
    "id": "000503"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first beatitude in the Sermon on the Mount?",
    "correctAnswer": "Blessed are the poor in spirit",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Blessed are those who mourn",
      "Blessed are the meek",
      "Blessed are the pure in heart"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:3",
    "id": "000504"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Jesus do first after coming down from the mountain?",
    "correctAnswer": "He heals a leper",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He teaches in the synagogue",
      "He goes again to preach",
      "He calls a disciple"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Luke",
      "Christ"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:1",
    "id": "000505"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disciple walked on the water to Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas",
      "Judas"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 14: 28,29",
    "id": "000506"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who asked Jesus if He is the Christ, the Son of God?",
    "correctAnswer": "Caiaphas",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Judas",
      "Pilatus",
      "Herod"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories": [
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 26:63",
    "id": "000507"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened when Jesus was baptized?",
    "correctAnswer": "The heavens were opened",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The earth shook",
      "The sun darkened",
      "An angel descended"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Christ"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 3:16",
    "id": "000508"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first disciple Jesus called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Jacobus",
      "Andrew"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 4:18",
    "id": "000509"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Jesus say to them when he walked on water to the disciples?",
    "correctAnswer": "I am, do not be afraid",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Do not be afraid, I am",
      "Walk to me",
      "I am the Way, do not be afraid"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Luke"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 14:27",
    "id": "000510"
  },
  {
    "question": "For how many silver pieces was Jesus betrayed?",
    "correctAnswer": "30",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "20",
      "40",
      "10"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 26:15",
    "id": "000511"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said to Jesus: You are the King of the Jews?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pilate",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Caiphas",
      "Herod",
      "The High Priest"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 27: 51, 52",
    "id": "000512"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened after Jesus was dead for 3 hours?",
    "correctAnswer": "The rocks split and the earth shook",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The earth was darkened for 3 hours",
      "The temple curtain was torn in two",
      "An angel descended"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 27: 51, 52",
    "id": "000513"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said: I have suffered much in a dream to do Your will?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pilate's wife",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The wife of Caiaphas",
      "The wife of Herod",
      "The wife of Judas"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 27:19",
    "id": "000514"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who found (saw) the empty tomb?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mary Magdalene and the other Mary",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Mary, mother of Jesus",
      "Peter and John",
      "Peter and James"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 28:1",
    "id": "000515"
  },
  {
    "question": "What said the angel first to the women at the tomb?",
    "correctAnswer": "Do not be afraid",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He is risen",
      "He is not here; He has risen",
      "He goes ahead quickly"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 28:5",
    "id": "000516"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Jesus give to his disciples after His resurrection?",
    "correctAnswer": "A command",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Holy Spirit",
      "A blessing",
      "A promise"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "categories": [
      "Acts",
      "Easter",
      "Pentecost"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 28:19",
    "id": "000517"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the fourth son of Jacob?",
    "correctAnswer": "Judah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Levi",
      "Dan",
      "Naphtali"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 29:35",
    "id": "000518"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the color of the second lamb in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Red",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "White",
      "Black",
      "Fawn"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 6:4",
    "id": "000519"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disciple was not on the mountain of transfiguration?",
    "correctAnswer": "Andreas",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "John",
      "Jacobus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew",
      "Mark",
      "Luke"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 9:28",
    "id": "000520"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people went into the ark of Noah?",
    "correctAnswer": "8",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "6",
      "4",
      "10"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 8:16",
    "id": "000521"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was not a son of Noah?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gomer",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sem",
      "Ham",
      "Japheth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 9:18",
    "id": "000522"
  },
  {
    "question": "From whom was Dan a son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bilhah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Leah",
      "Zilpah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 30:5",
    "id": "000523"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was fourth daughter of Zelophehad?",
    "correctAnswer": "Milcah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Naah",
      "Hoglah",
      "Tirzah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Numbers 27:1",
    "id": "000524"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who spoke for Job?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elihu",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Bildad",
      "Zophar",
      "Elifaz"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Job"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Job 32:2",
    "id": "000525"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which king fell by a falsehood in his territory?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ahabaziah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Joram",
      "Azariah",
      "Jotham"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Kings 1:2",
    "id": "000526"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was mother of Absalom?",
    "correctAnswer": "Maacah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Haggith",
      "Ahinoam",
      "Abigail"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 3:3",
    "id": "000527"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the final plague in Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hail and darkness",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Locusts and flies",
      "Lice and boils",
      "Frost and thunder"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 9:24",
    "id": "000528"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was queen mother of King Hezekiah?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hephzibah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jehosheba",
      "Abi",
      "Michal"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 36:3",
    "id": "000529"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many sons had Gideon?",
    "correctAnswer": "70",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "30",
      "50",
      "60"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 8:30",
    "id": "000530"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which judge was left-handed?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ehud",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jephthah",
      "Shamgar",
      "Othniel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:15",
    "id": "000531"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was tabernacle of gold made?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gold",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Silver",
      "Bronze",
      "Iron"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 25:31",
    "id": "000532"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was third son of Aaron?",
    "correctAnswer": "Eleazar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Nadab",
      "Abihu",
      "Ithamar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 6:22",
    "id": "000533"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which community did John write a letter to? John wrote a letter.",
    "correctAnswer": "Philadelphian",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Smyrna",
      "Pergamum",
      "Laodicea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts",
      "Revelation",
      "John"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:7",
    "id": "000534"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was no woman of Esau?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zilpah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ada",
      "Aholibamah",
      "Basemath"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 36: 2,3",
    "id": "000535"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was fourth son of Abraham and Keturah?",
    "correctAnswer": "Midian",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ishbak",
      "Medan",
      "Shuah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 25:2",
    "id": "000536"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who plotted to release Joseph from the pit?",
    "correctAnswer": "Reuben",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Simeon",
      "Judah",
      "Levi"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 37:29",
    "id": "000537"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who stood before Benjamin when they were at Jacob?",
    "correctAnswer": "Judah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Simeon",
      "Reuben",
      "Naftali"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 43:8-9",
    "id": "000538"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which son of Jacob will dwell at the havens of the sea?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zebulon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Reuben",
      "Gad",
      "Asher"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 49:13",
    "id": "000539"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet preached a funeral lamentation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hosea",
      "Micah",
      "Nahum"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Jonah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000540"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the father of Abram?",
    "correctAnswer": "Terah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Haran",
      "Nahor",
      "Serug"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26",
    "id": "000541"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many shekels of silver did Abraham pay to Ephron for Sarah's grave?",
    "correctAnswer": "400",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "200",
      "500",
      "600"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 23:16",
    "id": "000542"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Abraham when he died?",
    "correctAnswer": "175",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "150",
      "155",
      "180"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 25:7",
    "id": "000543"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who stayed with Joseph in Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Simeon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ruben",
      "Judah",
      "Zebulun"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 42:24",
    "id": "000544"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was firstborn son of Reuben?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hanoch",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Pallu",
      "Hezron",
      "Charmi"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 46:9",
    "id": "000545"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jacob was deceived, how many days?",
    "correctAnswer": "40",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "20",
      "30",
      "60"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 50:3",
    "id": "000546"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days was Jacob mourned at the Jordan?",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "5",
      "10"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 50:10",
    "id": "000547"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long did Joseph live?",
    "correctAnswer": "110",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "120",
      "130",
      "150"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 50:26",
    "id": "000548"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the second plague in Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Frogs",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lice",
      "Locusts and boils"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 8:16",
    "id": "000549"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days was there second plague in Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "4",
      "6"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 10:22",
    "id": "000550"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which day is a feast?",
    "correctAnswer": "5",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "2",
      "3",
      "6"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus",
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 20:12",
    "id": "000551"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which rows of the breastplate of Aaron were a ruby, an onyx and an amethyst?",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "4"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 28:19",
    "id": "000552"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isaiah was a prophet in the kingdom of Judah",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 1:1",
    "id": "000553"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isaiah had visions of the Lord, standing for angels and new ... and new earth",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 6:1",
    "id": "000554"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isaiah was a contemporary of King Saul",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 1:1",
    "id": "000555"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isaiah prophesied about new heavens and new ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Isaiah 65:17",
    "id": "000556"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeremiah was a prophet in the kingdom of Judah",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 1:1",
    "id": "000557"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeremiah prophesied only during the reign of King David",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 1:3",
    "id": "000558"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pashur took Jeremiah captive",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Not true"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 20:2",
    "id": "000559"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeremiah writes in his letter: Dan has made an end to ... and will not hear to me, and I will pray to you but you will not listen",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 29:12",
    "id": "000560"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel was a prophet in Babylon?",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 1:1-3",
    "id": "000561"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel became a watchman for Israel ... days",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "14",
      "30"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 3:15",
    "id": "000562"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel prophesied about new heavens and new ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 32:1",
    "id": "000563"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniel wrote in a dream: 'You shall fast ... days'",
    "correctAnswer": "21",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "7",
      "40"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 10:2-3",
    "id": "000564"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ezekiel prophesied about 430 years of Jerusalem's ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 29",
    "id": "000565"
  },
  {
    "question": "God made a promise to Abraham in ... BC",
    "correctAnswer": "2000",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1500",
      "1800",
      "2500"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12:4",
    "id": "000566"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet was in Babylon when God spoke to Daniel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jeremiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Daniel himself"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 9:2",
    "id": "000567"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Daniel ends with these words: 'But you, go your way, for the words are ... up to the time of the end.'",
    "correctAnswer": "sealed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "closed",
      "open",
      "broken"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel 12:9",
    "id": "000568"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Daniel was written in ... languages",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Daniel",
    "id": "000569"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letter to the Romans is Paul's ... letter",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Romans"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 16",
    "id": "000570"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul speaks about the new life through the Holy ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Romans",
      "1 Corinthians",
      "2 Corinthians",
      "Galatians",
      "Ephesians",
      "Colossians",
      "1 Thessalonians",
      "2 Thessalonians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Romans 8",
    "id": "000571"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul wrote the letter to the Galatians because of their ... to the gospel",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 1: 6,7",
    "id": "000572"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Galatians are ... to make the ... of Christ perfect and to fulfill the law",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Galatians 6:2",
    "id": "000573"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul speaks in the letter to the Ephesians about the ... of Christ",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 3: 17-19",
    "id": "000574"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes in Philippians: I can do all things through ... who gives me strength",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Philippians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Philippians 4:13",
    "id": "000575"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul warns in Colossians against ... teachings",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Colossians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians 2:8",
    "id": "000576"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul wrote Colossians while he was in ...",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Colossians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Colossians 4:10",
    "id": "000577"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul speaks in the letter to the Ephesians about the ... of Christ",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 3: 17-19",
    "id": "000578"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul wrote the letter to the ... on the love of Christ",
    "correctAnswer": "Not true",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "True"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "tf",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ephesians 3: 17-19",
    "id": "000579"
  },
  {
    "question": "And he said to ...: which of these times should you we know? You, me, the Lord do not keep one hour with us.",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Johannes",
      "Jakobus",
      "Matth\u00e9\u00fcs"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 26:40",
    "id": "000580"
  },
  {
    "question": "And so is it ...: The Lord is ... of the Lord.",
    "correctAnswer": "forever",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "thanked",
      "blessed",
      "praised"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 16:36",
    "id": "000581"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which book is David's psalm preserved?",
    "correctAnswer": "1 Chronicles",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1 Kings",
      "2 Kings",
      "2 Chronicles"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Chronicles 16: 7-36",
    "id": "000582"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which apostle: You have the words of eternal life?",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Andreans",
      "Johannes",
      "Jakobus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 6:68",
    "id": "000583"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disciple: Do not know where we will go?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Johannes",
      "Petrus",
      "Jakobus"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 11:16",
    "id": "000584"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disciple: He, we know not where we are going?",
    "correctAnswer": "Thomas",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lukas",
      "Andreans",
      "Johannes"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 14:5",
    "id": "000585"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which disciple: He, the Father, to You is named?",
    "correctAnswer": "Philip",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Johannes",
      "Petrus",
      "Andr\u00e9as"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 14:8",
    "id": "000586"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which port in Jerusalem is a healing well?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Sheep Gate",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Fish Gate",
      "The Golden Gate",
      "The Water Gate"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 5:2",
    "id": "000587"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many men had the Samaritan woman's husbands?",
    "correctAnswer": "Five",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "Seven",
      "Three"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 4:18",
    "id": "000588"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which well in Samaria did Jesus speak to a woman?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacob's Well",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The King's Well",
      "The Prophet's Well",
      "Abraham's Well"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 4:6",
    "id": "000589"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which well is in Sychar, where Jesus met a Samaritan woman?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jacob's Well",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Abraham's Well",
      "David's Well",
      "The King's Well"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 4:6",
    "id": "000590"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the 2nd miraculous sign Jesus performed in Cana?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Lost Coin Healing",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Turning Water to Wine",
      "Healing the Official's Son",
      "Feeding the 5000"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 4:46-54",
    "id": "000591"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pool in Jerusalem had five porches?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bethesda",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Siloam",
      "Hezekiah's Pool",
      "The Upper Pool"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "John 5:2",
    "id": "000592"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long were the disciples in the upper room?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ten days",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Three days",
      "Seven days",
      "Forty days"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 1:13",
    "id": "000593"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which gate is a healing well in Jerusalem?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Sheep Gate",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Golden Gate",
      "The Water Gate",
      "The Fish Gate"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 3:2",
    "id": "000594"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Samaritan woman's first husband?",
    "correctAnswer": "Five",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "Seven",
      "Three"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 16:18",
    "id": "000595"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which gate in Jerusalem is a healing well?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Sheep Gate",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Golden Gate",
      "The Water Gate",
      "The Fish Gate"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 3:2",
    "id": "000596"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days did the feast of Dedication (Hanukkah) last?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Three",
      "Five",
      "Seven"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 4:9",
    "id": "000597"
  }
]